Michael L. Shenk

Seattle, WA 98116 | Ph: 415.317.2341 | LinkedIn.com/in/MichaelShenk415 | E-Mail: Mike.L.Shenk@gmail.com GitHub.com/MLShenk | Portfolio: https://mlshenk.github.io/professional-portfolio/

Summary: Full-Stack Developer in Seattle, WA and graduate of U. of Washington full-time coding bootcamp. Professional background in sales and management includes success under pressure while maintaining sharp focus on details and end-goals. Utilizes technical training with previous experience to drive growth, provide responsive applications and develop efficient user experiences.

Technical Skills: React.js, Node.js, REST APIs, MySQL, MongoDB, MERN Stack, HTML/CSS

Projects

Project MixMe | Built using HTML, CSS, JS, and APIs that allows users to browse their favorite cocktails, search cocktail recipes by ingredient, play an interactive game to learn about their favorite cocktails, and find bars in their local area that serve the cocktails. Won two in-class awards for this project.

FlipIt | Interactive flashcard app that utilizes HTML, CSS, and JavaScript for the front end development and mySQL for back-end development. Users create an account then sign in to create, edit, and study flashcards covering material from a variety of subjects. Worked on the front-end development of this app and, as the project manager, guided the scrum team from brainstorming through the class presentation.

Experience

Conner Homes – Land Acquisition Specialist

Oct. 2019 - Feb. 2020

- Managed pipeline of 4500 potential leads for homebuilding development projects in the Greater Seattle area
- Converted numerous interested property sellers targeted by direct mailer campaign into land acquisition leads
- Tracked all finished lot sales and prepared budgets for new home-building projects with finance department

Regus Management Group – Community Manager

Feb. 2019 - Oct. 2019

- Drove client retention and raised NPS scores for tenants and increased office occupancy from 75% to 95%
- Hired, trained, and developed two Community Associates
- Managed accounts and day-to-day operations of 130 in-house and virtual office clients in Seattle's most iconic building

Enterprise Holdings, Inc. – Assistant Branch Manager

Oct. 2014 - Sept. 2018

- Achieved Top Performer distinction six times and Top 6 of sales matrix for entire year
- Led Oakland Airport branch to double income of Prior Year-to-Date, including \$1 million increase in total revenue in August 2016
- Acquired exclusive rental car referral business from four major accounts in San Francisco
- Managed daily rental operations and designed training programs for brand identity, sales, customer service, and operational logistics

Education

University of Washington Full Stack Web Development Certificate 12-week intensive web development bootcamp

Summer 2020

University of California, Berkeley

B.A., in American Studies;

Area of Concentration: Technology and Urban Inequality

Minor: City & Regional Planning

Class of 2014